Sooner or later, a man who wears two faces forgets which one is real.
Primal Fear is a crime, drama, mystery film directed by Gregory Hoblit.
Defense attorney Martin Vail takes on jobs for money and
prestige rather than any sense of the greater good.
His latest case involves an altar boy, accused of
brutally murdering the archbishop of Chicago.
Vail finds himself up against his ex-pupil and ex-lover, but as the case progresses and the Church's dark secrets
are revealed, Vail finds that what appeared a simple case takes on a darker, more dangerous aspect.
Martin Vail, played by Richard Gere.
Janet Venable, played by Laura Linney.
Aaron/Roy Stampler, played by Edward Norton.
Shaughnessy, played by John Mahoney.
Shoat, played by Alfre Woodard.
Molly, played by Frances McDormand.
Primal Fear is a 1996 American crime legal drama mystery thriller film directed by Gregory Hoblit, based on
the 1993 novel of the same name by William Diehl, written by Steve Shagan and Ann Biderman.
It stars Richard Gere, Laura Linney, John Mahoney, Alfre Woodard,
Frances McDormand, and Edward Norton in his film debut.
The film follows a Chicago-based defense attorney who believes that his
client, an altar boy, is not guilty of murdering a Catholic bishop.
The film was a box office success and received positive reviews,
with Norton's performance earning critical praise.
Norton won the Golden Globe Award for Best Supporting Actor – Motion Picture, and was nominated for the
Academy Award for Best Supporting Actor and the BAFTA Award for Best Actor in a Supporting Role.
The film explores themes of chicago, illinois, death penalty,
child abuse, corruption, based on novel or book.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and emotional.